<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on MFEprimer</title>
    <link>https://www.mfeprimer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on MFEprimer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.mfeprimer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MFEprimer-3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.mfeprimer.com/mfeprimer-3.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mfeprimer.com/mfeprimer-3.1/</guid>
      <description>MFEprimer-3.1 Big change from v3.0
Major changes from v3.0  merge several tools into one single execute file mfeprimer support major platforms: Linux, Mac and Windows bug fixed and faster than v3.0 fix thermodynamics calculation bugs for dimers and hairpins local web server version is available  Summary of different versions Before getting started, I&amp;rsquo;d like to make a summary for different versions. Please choose the right version for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.mfeprimer.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mfeprimer.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications  MFEprimer-3.0: Quality Control for PCR Primers. Nucleic Acids Research (2019). https://dx.doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkz351. [NAR, 2019] sRNAPrimerDB: Comprehensive primer design and search web service for small non-coding RNAs[J]. [Bioinformatics, 2018] CRISPR-offinder: a CRISPR guide RNA design and off-target searching tool for user-defined protospacer adjacent motif[J]. [International journal of biological sciences, 2017] Wubin Qu# and Chenggang Zhang. Selecting Specific PCR Primers with MFEprimer. In PCR Primer Design, edited by Chhandak Basu, 1275, 201-213: Springer New York, 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online-server</title>
      <link>https://www.mfeprimer.com/online-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mfeprimer.com/online-server/</guid>
      <description> Download and Online Servers Online server  https://mfeprimer3.igenetech.com/ [version 3.0] web server funded by iGeneTech, a company aims to provide kit and service for target capture and sequencing, also is the company the author works for. http://124.207.243.56:8081/ [version 3.1, for test] web server funded by Prof. Dongsheng Zhao (AMMS, 军事医学科学院). Currently, there is only human genome (hg19) available and will add other genomes later.  Download  Download: https://github.com/quwubin/MFEprimer-3.0/releases/ Doc for install and usage  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MFEprimer-2.0</title>
      <link>https://www.mfeprimer.com/old-versions/mfeprimer-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mfeprimer.com/old-versions/mfeprimer-2.0/</guid>
      <description>MFEprimer-2.0 Introduction MFEprimer-2.0: A fast thermodynamics-based program for checking PCR primer specificity
Evaluating the specificity of polymerase chain reaction (PCR) primers is an essential step in PCR primer design. The MFEprimer-2.0 server allows users to check primer specificity against genomic DNA and messenger RNA/complementary DNA sequence databases quickly and easily. MFEprimer-2.0 uses a k-mer index algorithm to accelerate the search process for primer binding sites and uses thermodynamics to evaluate binding stability between each primer and its DNA template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MFEprimer-1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.mfeprimer.com/old-versions/mfeprimer-1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mfeprimer.com/old-versions/mfeprimer-1.0/</guid>
      <description>MFEprimer-1.0 Introduction MFEprimer: multiple factor evaluation of the specificity of PCR primers. We developed a program named MFEprimer for evaluating the specificity of PCR primers based on multiple factors, including sequence similarity, stability at the 3’-end of the primer, melting temperature, GC content and number of binding sites between the primer and DNA templates. MFEprimer can help the user to select more suitable primers before running either standard or multiplex PCR reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>